Guide to the Gertrude Estelle Denn papers, 1938-2002 MS 765
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Gertrude Estelle Denn papers
1938-2002
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Denn, Meyer
MS 765
0.25 Linear Feet 1 box
News clippings, a dance card, reunion and senior class night programs, a high school yearbook, and photographs record events in Gertrude Denn's life - predominantly in the 1940s.
Biographical / Historical
Gertrude "Gertie" Rosenzweig was born June 25, 1923, in Houston, Fort Bend County, Texas. She grew up in Houston and attended San Jacinto high school, graduating in 1940. Gertie married Sidney Denn -- a native of Bay City -- on September 1, 1946 at the Rice Hotel in Houston.
She and Sidney moved to New Orleans, Lousiana in Decemeber of 1946 to enable Sidney to work for Gertie's's brother, Leon. The two returned to Bay City the following year, and Sidney went into business with his brothers. Gertie and Sidney had four children: Bernard Ralph, Steven Howard, Brian Alan, and Meyer. She was a "Lifetime" member of Hadassah and volunteered her time as a pianist for many Jewish organizations throughout the area. Sidney and Gertie were members of Shearith Israel Congregation of Wharton, and were charter members of Beth David Center in Bay City.
Gertrude Denn died February 24, 2015 in Houston and is buried in the Shearith Israel Cemetery in Wharton.
Excerpted from: http://www.usgenwebsites.org/TXMatagorda/family_denn_sidney.htm
Scope and Contents
One box containing news clippings, a dance card, a high school yearbook, programs, and photographs documents events in Gertrude Denn's life, 1938-2002. Of particular interest is a 1940 San Jacinto High School yearbook.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Meyer Denn donated the papers in March 2018.
Arrangement
The materials in this collection have been arranged in six series as follows: Series I: Artifacts; Series II: Books; Series III: News Clippings; Series IV: Newsletters; Series V: Photographs; Series VI: Programs
Index Terms
Subjects
World War (1939-1945)
Document Types
yearbooks; clippings (information artifacts); photographs; newsletters; programs (documents)
Subjects (Persons)
Denn, Meyer
- Series I: Artifacts, 1940
  - Dance card for Gamma Deuteron of Alpha Epsilon Pi Fall Formal, 1940-11-09 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II: Books, 1940
  - El Orso - San Jacinto High School yearbook, 1940 (Box 1)
- Series III: News Clippings, 1942-2002
  - And One of These Shall Reign as Queen Esther - The Jewish Herald Voice, 1942-03-05 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Houston Students Form All-Girl Orchestra, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Class of '40 Lunches at Luby's - The Campus Cub, 2002-12 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series IV: Newsletters, 1943
  - The Magnolia Home Guard newsletter, 1943-11-18 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Series V: Photographs, 1938-1977
  - Photographs, 1938-1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - San Jacinto High class of '40, 50th reunion group photo, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series VI: Programs, 1940; 1990
  - San Jacinto Senior High "Class Night" program, 1940-05-30 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - San Jacinto High School class of '40 50th reunion program and directory, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)